{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "At this battle, Congreve rockets fired into American forces caused confusion, leaving Joshua Barney’s flotilla force of African-Americans on its own. Tobias Stansbury dug artillery earthworks on Lowndes Hill during this battle. William Winder’s forces were defeated at this battle by Robert Ross. This battle’s namesake “Races” led to the need for Paul Jennings and Dolley Madison to save a presidential portrait. For ten points, name this 1814 victory for the British in Maryland that led to the burning of Washington, DC.",
      "answer": "Battle of BladenAsburg"
    },
    {
      "question": "This polity took a more isolationist stance after the battle of Rio Salado, at which the Marinids were defeated. This polity’s last ruler, Boabdil, went into an almost five decade exile in Fes. This polity’s rulers were named after Muhammad I’s ancestor, Nasr the Red, and “red” is the translation for this polity’s best known work of architecture. This polity was ruled from the Alhambra and ended in 1492 after its conquest by Castile. For ten points, name this polity and city of southern Spain.",
      "answer": [
        "Nasrid Emirate of Granada",
        "Nasrid Kingdom of Granada R"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This author wrote a “funeral sermon” that opens, “Weep not, weep not, She is not dead.” This author coined the term “Red Summer” to describe racial violence in 1919. The narrator of a novel by this author tours Europe with a benefactor while playing ragtime music, then moves to New York after viewing a brutal lynching. This author wrote a poem often considered the “Black National Anthem” that includes, “Lift every voice and sing.” For ten points, name this author of God’s Trombones and Autobiography of an Ex-Colored Man.",
      "answer": "James Weldon Johnson D"
    },
    {
      "question": "This conflict included a surprise raid on Maaten el-Sarra, for which French forces were blamed despite not being involved. The French were, however, participants in this conflict as part of the larger Operation Epervier. Hissene Habre was given Stinger missiles by the US to use in this conflict. This conflict gets its name from the makeshift “Technicals” employed by FANT and FAP guerrilla forces against Muammar Gaddafi’s army. For ten points, name this war fought over control of the Aouzou Strip by Chad and Libya.",
      "answer": "Great Toyota War"
    },
    {
      "question": "The site of a university created by Benedik Kischdy, this city was captured in 1938 by a country that called it “Kassa.” A pact signed in this city in 1374 allowed a daughter of Louis I to gain the Polish throne upon the death of Casimir the Great. A government formed in this city in 1945 was led by prime ministers Zdenek Fierlinger and Klement Gottwald but only lasted for three years. Located near the eastern Slovak Ore Mountains, for ten points, name this second-largest city of Slovakia.",
      "answer": [
        "Kosice",
        "Kassa before mentioned T"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "A battle partly named for this cardinal number took place in Henrico County and included a costly victory by George McClellan against Joseph Johnston. This number names a series of clashes of which Daniel Harvey Hill said, “It wasn’t war, it was murder,” after the Battle of Malvern Hill. A battle also called “Fair Oaks” includes this number and occurred a month before a series of battles with this number F in which Robert E. Lee drove Union forces away from Richmond. For ten points, name this number of Days and Pines in these 1862 battles.",
      "answer": "Seven"
    },
    {
      "question": "Lack of government support was to blame for this battle’s outcome according to Gary Bernsten, the head of the CIA’s Jawbreaker team. Tommy Franks was blamed for not sealing off escape routes at this battle, allowing its target to flee to Parachinar. Delta operative Dalton Fury’s account of this battle A blames Pakistan’s poor border security for its result. For ten points, name this December 2001 battle, named for a cave complex in Afghanistan’s White Mountains, that failed to capture a fleeing Osama bin Laden.",
      "answer": "Battle of Tora Bora"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to legend, when this man was killed in his tent by a warrior named Brodir, a boy was wounded by the same sword stroke that beheaded this man, but the boy’s wound was immediately healed. This winner at the Battle of Balech Lechta was buried at Armagh after he died in April 1014. That battle wasRpart of a rebellion that started while this man conquered Ulster. For ten points, name this ruler who died at the Battle of Clontarf after ruling for twelve years as High King of Ireland.",
      "answer": [
        "Brian Boru",
        "Brian Borumac Cennetig,",
        "Brian Boramha,",
        "Brian Boruma"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This film ends with its protagonist relating how, during Roman triumphs, slaves would whisper into a conquerors ear, “That all is fleeting.” That protagonist of this film smiles smugly after another character realizes that the protagonist had arrived in Messina before him as part of the Allied invasion of Sicily. In Dthis film, the protagonist claims, “No bastard ever won a war by dying for his country,” in a speech given to the Third Army. Bernard Montgomery is a rival of the protagonist in, for ten points, what biographical film about a namesake U.S. general?",
      "answer": "Patton"
    },
    {
      "question": "The president of this organization’s Chicago branch established the Bethesda Day Nursery. A leader of this organization discussed her “Do Nothing” policy in a speech given to the “White Ribbon Army.” Matilda Carse began this organization’s journal, The Union Signal, and Carrie Nation started one of its chapters. Annie Wittenmeyer was the first president of, for ten points, what women’s organization led by Frances Willard to promote prohibition?",
      "answer": [
        "Woman’s Christian Temperance Union",
        "WCTU T"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Students at this university protested the appointment of Jane Fernandes after the retirement of President Irving King Jordan. Students demanded thFe resignation of Jane Bassett Spilman and burned effigies of Elizabeth Zinser at this university during the DPN movement. This school’s founder was inspired by Alice Cogswell, who suffered from “spotted fever.” For ten points, name this Washington, D.C. university where students took part in the Deaf President Now protests.",
        "answer": "Gallaudet University"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Gallaudet graduates traditionally have their diplomas signed by the U.S. president, a tradition that began during the first term of this president, himself an 1843 West Point graduate. A",
        "answer": "Ulysses S. Grant"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The losing side of this battle initially repulsed the winning side at Oberglau under Ferdinand de Marsin, but a successful crossing of the River Nebel caused the Bavarian army to retreat. At this battle, the Duc de Tallard was captured by the Grand Alliance forces of Eugene of Savoy and the Duke of Marlborough. For ten points, name this decisive 1704 battle during the War of the Spanish Succession, the namesake of a palace built for one of its victorious commanders.",
        "answer": "Battle of Blenheim R"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Blenheim Palace is the residence of the Dukes of Marlborough and the birthplace of this British prime minister, the grandson of the 7th Duke of Marlborough.",
        "answer": "Winston Churchill"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "After the overthrow of this country’s prime minister, Timoci Bavadra, another country launched Operation Morris Dance. Following that 1987 coup, Sitiveni Rabuka declared this country a republic. Kamisese Mara is considered the founding father of this country, in which Mahendra Chaudhry was taken D hostage by George Speight. This country, united by King Cakobau, elected Frank Bainimarama as prime minister in 2007. For ten points, name this Melanesian archipelagic nation.",
        "answer": "Republic of Fiji"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "In 1865, many workers from what is now this country were abducted to work on Fiji’s cotton plantations. From August 1942 to February 1943, U.S. and Japanese forces fought at this country’s island of Guadalcanal.",
        "answer": "Solomon Islands T"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Ida C. Craddock was arrested for violating this law by promoting the spiritual movement of Dianism. This law was passed in response to Victoria Woodhull and Tennessee Claflin’s expose on Henry Ward Beecher. Margaret Sanger was arrested for violating this law after opening a birth control clinic in New York City, and its namesake was a special agent of the U.S. Postal Service. For ten points, what is this F law, named for an anti-vice activist, that banned the passing of obscene materials through the mail?",
        "answer": "Comstock Laws"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The prohibition on the mailing of birth control in the Comstock Laws was effectively ended by this 1965 Supreme Court case that protects marital privacy against state restrictions on contraception.",
        "answer": "Griswold v. Connecticut A"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This “Zola of the Occult” abandoned a cycle of historic plays but did complete a story about Olaus Petri’s struggle to free the Church of Sweden from Roman domination, Master Olof. This author related his struggles with mental illness in the autobiographical novel, Inferno. This author of A Dream Play and The Ghost Sonata wrote a play in which the protagonist commits suicide with a razor, Miss Julie. For ten points, name this author of The Red Room, considered the “Father of modern Swedish literature.”",
        "answer": "August Strindberg"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Some of Strindberg’s work is based on the ideas of this Swedish theologian, known for his book onRthe afterlife, Heaven and Hell.",
        "answer": "Emanuel Swedenborg"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Anna Louise Strong relocated to this country after being expelled by a northern neighbor. Jack Belden reported on a conflict in this country, though he refused to conduct interviews with its leader in a cave. It’s not India, but Douglas MacArthur accused Agnes Smedley of espionage following the publishing of her book, Battle Hymn of...[this country]. Red Star over...[this country] titles Edgar Snow’s account of a campaign aided by communist journalist, Otto Braun. For ten points, name this Asian country. D",
        "answer": "People’s Republic of China"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Anna Louise Strong developed a friendship with this African-American leader of the Niagara Movement and author of The Souls of Black Folk.",
        "answer": "William Edward Burghardt Du Bois T"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A bridge constructed between this city and Fairhaven helped spur early growth. The oldest continuously operating jail in the United States is in this city, where demands for pay raises sparked a 30,000-man strong textile strike in 1928. The Charles W. Morgan was built in this city that lies on Buzzard Bay. The toggling harpoon was invented in this city for its most famous industry. For ten points, F name this Massachusetts city in which Hermann Melville worked as a whaler.",
        "answer": "New Bedford, Massachusetts"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The whaling ship Charles W. Morgan is now on display in this Connecticut port city with one of the largest U.S. maritime museums, the site of a namesake massacre when colonists set fire to a Pequot village.",
        "answer": "Mystic, Connecticut A"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "During this war, the 12th Infantry Regiment was decimated at the Battle of Sand Butte. A leader of one side in this war asked Edward Canby to “give us a home in our country” before cutting his throat. This war opened at the Battle of Lost River, which began after the US Army forced a band of the namesake tribe back to the Klamath Reservation. Before his execution during this war, Kintpuash, known as “Captain Jack,” fled to Lava Beds National Monument. For ten points, name this 1872-73 war in northeastern California.",
        "answer": [
          "Modoc War",
          "Modoc Campaign,",
          "Lava Beds War before mentioned R"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "One member of the 12th Infantry present at Utah Beach on D-Day was this enigmatic author of the short stories, “Slight Rebellion off Madison” and “A Perfect Day for Bananafish.”",
        "answer": "J.D. Salinger"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "According to the Bamboo Annals, this figure died during a hunting trip on Mount Kuaiji and was then buried in Shaoxing. During his reign, this figure divided his kingdom into nine zhou or provinces. This figure’s wisdom impressed King Shun so much that he was made heir to the throne over Shun’s own D son. This figure helped his father, Gun, utilize growing soil to accomplish his most noted task. For ten points, name this likely legendary founder of the Xia dynasty, who stopped the flooding of the Yellow River.",
        "answer": [
          "Yu the Great",
          "Da Yu"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Xia dynasty may have been legendary, but historically the era of the Xia was followed by this dynasty that ruled China from 1600 to 1046 BC, when it was overthrown by the Zhou dynasty.",
        "answer": [
          "Shang dynasty",
          "Yin dynasty T"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man’s flag included a six-pointed star and the double-bladed Dhu’l-Fiqar sword. This man, who was given the name “Silver Arm” for his silver prosthetic limb, negotiated with Andrea Doria for the release of Turget Reis. While allied with France, this man led the Siege of Nice [neece] in 1543, a decade after he conquered Tunis and five years after he faced an attack from Charles V. For ten points, name this F Sultan of Algiers, an Ottoman admiral known as “Redbeard.”",
        "answer": [
          "Hayreddin Barbarossa",
          "either underlined portion,",
          "Hizir Hayrettin Pasha,",
          "Hizir Reis"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Barbarossa faced Andrea Doria and the navy of the Holy League at the Battle of Preveza, fought in the same waters as this 31 BC battle at which a defeat of Marc Antony allowed Octavian to consolidate his power.",
        "answer": "Battle of ActiumA"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Populism in the United States",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Democrat who gave the Cross of Gold speech, nicknamed the “Great Commoner” F",
          "answer": "William Jennings Bryan"
        },
        {
          "question": "Movement that aimed to expand a bimetallic money system",
          "answer": "Free Silver"
        },
        {
          "question": "Tax promoted in the Ocala Demands, eventually adopted in the 16th Amendment",
          "answer": "Income tax A"
        },
        {
          "question": "Platform adopted in the largest city of Nebraska, described as a Second Declaration of Independence",
          "answer": "Omaha Platform"
        },
        {
          "question": "Iowa representative and first Populist presidential candidate",
          "answer": "James Baird Weaver"
        },
        {
          "question": "Protest march of unemployed workers on Washington, D.C., led by a namesake Ohio businessman",
          "answer": "Coxey’s Army R"
        },
        {
          "question": "State in which a fusion of the Populists and the Republican Party took control of the state legislature in 1894",
          "answer": "North Carolina"
        },
        {
          "question": "Last Populist presidential nominee, a Georgia newspaper editor",
          "answer": "Thomas Edward Watson D T"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Time of Troubles",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Russian imperial ruling house whose leader became Tsar at the end of the Time of Troubles F",
          "answer": "House of Romanov"
        },
        {
          "question": "Dynasty founded by a Varangian prince whose extinction began the period",
          "answer": "Rurikid Dynasty"
        },
        {
          "question": "Usurper Tsar who reigned from 1598 to 1605, the subject of a Pushkin play",
          "answer": "Boris Godunov A"
        },
        {
          "question": "Name of Ivan the Terrible’s youngest son, who was impersonated by three pretenders",
          "answer": "Dmitry Ivanovich, of Uglich or of Moscow"
        },
        {
          "question": "Empire whose military commander Jacob de la Gardie lost the Battle of Klushino",
          "answer": [
            "Sweden",
            "Swedish Empire"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "King of Poland who used this period as an opportunity to invade",
          "answer": "Sigismund III Vasa R"
        },
        {
          "question": "Boyar who succeeded the first imposter pretender, forced to become a monk after he was deposed",
          "answer": [
            "Vasili Shuisky",
            "Vasili IV of Russia,",
            "Basil IV of Russia"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Region on the southern bank of the Gulf of Finland, ceded to a neighbor after a namesake war",
          "answer": "Ingria D"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "T",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Capital city renovated by the New Order regime F",
          "answer": "Jakarta"
        },
        {
          "question": "Country that ruled over the colony through its “United East India Company”",
          "answer": [
            "The Netherlands",
            "Holland,",
            "Nederland"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "First president of Indonesia who implemented “Guided Democracy” before being deposed by Suharto",
          "answer": [
            "Sukarno",
            "Kusno Sosrodihardjo A"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "7th president of Indonesia, re-elected in 2019",
          "answer": [
            "Joko Widodo",
            "Jokowi,",
            "Mulyono"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Indonesian city where the Non-Aligned Movement was formed at a 1955 conference",
          "answer": "Bandung"
        },
        {
          "question": "Party blamed for the 30th September Movement and targeted in the mass killings of 1965-66",
          "answer": [
            "Indonesian Communist Party",
            "the PKI,",
            "Partai Komunis Indonesia R"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Hindu kingdom established by Raden Wijaya on Java that reached its height under Hayam Wuruk",
          "answer": "Majapahit Empire"
        },
        {
          "question": "Buddhist maritime empire centered around Palembang that controlled all trade through the Sunda and Malacca straits",
          "answer": "Srivijaya Empire D T"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This politician led a filibuster with Robert La Follette of the Armed Ship Bill in 1917. Other defiant stances by this man include hisFcrossing of the aisle to support Al Smith in 1928. This politician announced changes to House rules on St. Patrick’s Day in 1910 to oust tyrannical Speaker, (20 pts)",
        "“Uncle Joe” Cannon. This man was featured as one of the “Courageous Eight” in John F. Kennedy’s Profiles in Courage for protesting US entry into World War One. This politician authored a bill outlawing (10 pts)",
        "“yellow-dog” contracts with Fiorello LaGuardia. For ten points, name this progressive senator from Nebraska."
      ],
      "answer": "George William Norris A"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Plans for this event were initially laid out after the Four Days Battle. Upnor Castle and the Gillingham line failed to prevent this event, during which Unity was the first ship lost. Royal James and Royal Oak were burnt at Chatham dockyards during this event. The (20 pts)",
        "Royal Charles was captured during this event, and its royal arms are on display at the Rijksmuseum. Johan De Witt masterminded this event, and (10 pts)",
        "Dutch forces during this event were commanded by Michel de Ruyter. For ten points, name this successful surprise attack by the Dutch on the English fleet which ended the Second Anglo-Dutch War."
      ],
      "answer": "Raid on the Medway R"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The leader of the winning side at this battle swore he would take the Aruna road, through what is today known as the “Northern Triangle,” as his “nostrils [were] rejuvenated with life and satisfaction.” The victors at this battle looted the countryside of the Jezreel Valley. Details about this battle came from the scribe Tjaneni and were recorded in the (20 pts)",
        "Hall of Annals at the Temple of Amun. This battle was fought a year after its victor succeeded his stepmother Hatshepsut. The (10 pts)",
        "Canaanites and the King of Kadesh were defeated at this battle by Thutmose III. For ten points, name this 1457 BC battle. DANSWER: Battle of Megiddo (4) Historian John Paynter described Judson Diggs’s role as a “Judas” in this event. Horace Mann served as a lawyer to those indicted in this event including Captain Daniel Drayton and Edward Sayres, who owned its namesake. The Salem was sent out by (+) slaveowners in this event and captured a ship at Point Lookout. Paul Jennings, a former slave to James Madison helped plan this event, and after it occurred, Henry Ward Beecher’s church freed the (*) Edmonson sisters. 77 people attempted escape in, for ten points, what 1848 incident in Washington, D.C, the largest non-violent slave escape attempt in America?"
      ],
      "answer": "Pearl Incident T"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This poet claimed “to live in mankind is far more than to live in a name” in his elegy to John Altgeld, “The Eagle That is Forgotten.” A “bronzed, lank man” in a “high top-hat” is unable to sleep in one of this author’s poems because “too many peasants fight” as he paces through (20 pts)",
        "Springfield, Illinois. The refrain “Are you washed in the blood of the lamb?” is F repeated in another of this man’s poems about the death of the founder of the (10 pts)",
        "Salvation Army. For ten points, name this poet of “Abraham Lincoln Walks at Midnight” and “General William Booth Enters into Heaven.”"
      ],
      "answer": "Vachel Linsday"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This leader died on a mountain now named after him during the Siege of Panticapeum. This man eliminated his brother, Chrestus, and his mother, Laodice, to become sole heir to A the throne. Pliny the Elder related that this man could speak the languages of (20 pts)",
        "all 22 nations he governed. This man was defeated in a series of conflicts that pitted him against military leaders like Lucius Lucullus. Delphi’s treasury was sacked by Lucius Cornelius Sulla in the first conflict against this one-time ruler of (10 pts)",
        "Asia Minor. For ten points, name this king of Pontus and formidable opponent of Rome."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Mithridates VI Eupator",
        "Mithridates the Great"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man’s wife, Hannah Wilkinson, became the first American woman to receive a patRent. As a child, this man worked at Jedediah Strutt’s operation which utilized a water frame. This man employed the “Rhode Island System” for his operations and built The Old Green (20 pts)",
        "Mill. With William Almy and Moses Brown, this man used Richard Arkwright’s ideas to build a water-powered mill in Pawtucket. Name this (10 pts)",
        "“traitor” to England who built, for ten points, the first water mills in the United States, a man whom Andrew Jackson called, the “father of the American Industrial Revolution.”"
      ],
      "answer": "Samuel Slater D"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The hereditary fudai branch of these people was the origin of each of the “Four Great Generals.” The policy of sankin-kotai required these people to leave their han every other year to live in the capital. During the (20 pts)",
        "Meiji Restoration the kuge merged with this class to form the kazoku. With a name translating to “large land,” these people were forced to cut down on the size of their (10 pts)",
        "samurai armies under Tokugawa Ieyasu. For ten points, name these powerful Japanese feudal lords, second only to the shogun."
      ],
      "answer": "Daimyo"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man is depicted within a crowd witnessing a scene from Augustine’s City of God in a painting he commissioned titled La Gloria. On the advice of Pietro Aretino, one portrait of this man alludes to St. George despite his being too (20 pts)",
        "gout-stricken to ride a horse. An eagle carrying an olive branch flies over this man’s head in a painting by Anthony van Dyck. In one portrait, this man is depicted emerging from a forest on horseback during a victory against the Schmalkaldic League. (10 pts)",
        "Titian painted a portrait of, for ten points, what Holy Roman Emperor “at Muhlberg”?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Charles V, Holy Roman Emperor",
        "Carlos I,",
        "Charles I of Spain T"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Jesse Buel edited the primary newspaper of this group. The man who coined the name of this group claimed he “had never known a body of men who possessed so much power and used it so well.” Azariah Flagg served as Comptroller of the state in which this group was located. This group fell apart after (20 pts)",
        "William Marcy lost an election to William Seward. F Thurlow Weed coined the name for this group, one of whom would face the (10 pts)",
        "Panic of 1837 as president. For ten points, Martin van Buren was a member of what group that dominated New York state politics in the early nineteenth century?"
      ],
      "answer": "Albany Regency"
    }
  ]
}